Juli A. Brady

Junior Developer



julibrady@gmail.com 510.207.5031 LinkedIn: /in/julibrady Github: jabrad0 Twitter: @juli_brady www.julibrady.com



ABOUT ME

In 2014, I began my journey to become a software developer and I am now seeking full-time, entry-level opportunities.

I acquired my Civil Engineering license in 2008 from the State of California. I have been an environmental engineer since 2003, specializing in soil and groundwater remediation.

My professional experience has included: managing a small business, managing projects, coordinating with clients, training staff, designing and constructing remediation systems, evaluating data, and writing technical reports.

I bring a professional-level of experience and engineering ability to my new career as a developer, in addition to a proven track record of hard work and success.



TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow

Hackbright Academy, September 2014 to December 2014 Graduated Hackbright Academy, a highly selective (7.5% acceptance rate) full-time, 10-week, full-stack software engineering immersion program in San Francisco, California.

Curriculum Included:

Backend: Python, Flask, SQL, SQLAlchemy Frontend: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS Industry tools: CLI, GIT, Pair Programming, Deployment CS: Data Structures and Algorithms, Best Practices

Technical Online Learning

Treehouse Academy, January 2015 to Present Udacity, October 2015 to Present Coursera, February 2015



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Civil/Environmental Engineer

July 2003 to September 2014

Senior Environmental Engineer

Streamborn | Berkeley, CA | October 2013–September 2014

- Prepared proposals and cost estimates for clients.
- Interacted with clients and government regulators daily.
- · Made on-the-spot project decisions in the field.
- · Managed simultaneous projects, budgets, and deadlines.

Junior Environmental Engineer

Iris Environmental | Oakland, CA | April 2011–September 2013

- Collaborated with teams regarding best project strategies.
- Managed multiple internal staff and professional vendors.
- Developed a sampling program and trained staff on best use.

Junior Environmental Engineer

Streamborn | Berkeley, CA | November 2006–April 2011

- · Projected and managed project budgets.
- · Designed and constructed remediation systems.
- Coordinated and planned all components of field work.
- Managed day-to-day operations of a small business.

Staff Engineer

Kennedy/Jenks | Sacramento, CA | July 2003–November 2006

- Conducted field work to investigate contaminated soil and groundwater.
- Produced project investigation reports.
- · Provided QA/QC on large amounts of investigation data.



SKILLS





PROJECTS

Getgo (5-week solo project)

Designed a web application allowing users to plan an art and wine stroll through Oakland CA by bike from any location within the city.

Deployed: https://getartandgo.herokuapp.com

Github: jabrad0/Getgo.

Stack: Python, Flask, JavaScript, JQuery, Jinja2, HTML, CSS,

Google Maps API, Yelp API

Spiritual Corky (1-week solo project)

Created a twitterbot program that generates a mash-up of quotes from the films "Jesus Christ Superstar" and "Waiting for Guffman" using Markov chains.

Twitter: @Spiritual_Corky Github: jabrad0/Spiritual_Corky Stack: Python, Twitter API

Udacity Front End Nanodegree (6-month online project)

Completed a series of classes to create a portfolio of projects highlighting front end development skills.

Deployed: https://www.julibrady.com Github: https://github.com/jabrad0/portfolio

Stack: Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, HTML5 Canvas,

Bootstrap, Grunt, Google Maps API



EDUCATION

Masters of Engineering, Biosystems and Agricultural

University of California, Davis Davis, CA | 2001–2003 Published two first author publications in peer-reviewed journals.

Bachelor of Engineering, Biosystems and Agricultural

University of Kentucky Lexington, KY | 1995–2000



LICENSURE

Professional Civil Engineer

California PE License #C72579